Guide to the Eva Overton Lewis and Julian Herman Lewis, MD, PhD Collection circa 1887-2015
University of Chicago Library
Lewis, Eva Overton and Julian Herman Lewis, MD, PhD Collection
circa 1887-2015
40 linear feet (29 boxes, 1 oversize folder)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Julian Herman Lewis (1891-1989) was a pathologist, educator, and author of The Biology of the Negro (1942), a groundbreaking investigation of contemporary scientific data and literature on African-American physiology and pathology that resisted and rebuked scientific notions of racial inferiority. His wife, Eva Overton Lewis (1893-1945), was the daughter of entrepreneur Anthony Overton and a graduate of the University of Chicago. The collection includes personal ephemera, correspondence, photographs and negatives, one DVD, newspapers, textiles, and memorabilia. Materials date between circa 1887 and 2015, with the bulk of the material dating between the 1890s and the 1940s. The collection is primarily a family collection, documenting the personal lives of Eva Overton Lewis, Julian Herman Lewis, their parents, and their children. It is a record of middle and upper-class African-American life in Chicago and Cairo, Illinois in the first half of the 20th century.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Eva Overton Lewis was born on September 12, 1893 to Anthony Overton (1864-1946) and Clara Gregg Overton (1867-1912) in Wanamaker, Oklahoma. Eva had three siblings: Everett Van Overton (1889-1960), Mabel Helena Overton Fowler (1891-1949), and Frances Madison Overton Hill (1894-1966). The family lived for a time in Kansas and Missouri before settling in Chicago, Illinois. Anthony Overton was a businessman and lawyer. He published the weekly newspaper The Chicago Bee and Half-Century Magazine, and established the Overton Hygienic Manufacturing Company, the Douglass National Bank, the Great Northern Realty Company, and the Victory Life Insurance Company.
Eva graduated from high school in Kansas City, Kansas and earned her A.B. from the University of Chicago in 1916 where she was a charter member of Beta Chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha sorority. (She was later a charter member of Theta Omega, the graduate chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha in 1922). Eva was involved in her father's businesses, including as a secretary for the Overton Hygienic Manufacturing Company. She married Julian Herman Lewis on September 12, 1918. Eva and Julian had three surviving children: Gloria Julienne Lewis (1920-1998), Julian Herman Lewis, Jr. (1921-2001), and John Overton Lewis (1928-2021).
Julian Herman Lewis was born on May 26, 1891 in Shawneetown, Illinois, to educators John Calhoun Lewis (circa 1857-1945) and Cordelia O. Lewis (circa 1867-1933, née Scott). John Calhoun Lewis and Cordelia O. Lewis met at Berea College in Kentucky. Julian had two sisters: Laura Louise Lewis Young (1893?-1969) and Clara Vesta Lewis Caldwell (1893-1979). Julian graduated Phi Beta Kappa from the University of Illinois in 1911 and earned an M.A. in 1912. He went on to earn a Ph.D. in physiology and pathology from the University of Chicago in 1915. His dissertation was published in the Journal of Infectious Diseases and he was awarded the Howard Taylor Ricketts Prize for "the student presenting the best results of research in Pathology or Bacteriology."
Julian completed his medical degree at Rush Medical College in 1917 (the school later awarded him the Benjamin Rush Medal in 1971). That same year, he was appointed as an Instructor to the Department of Pathology at the University of Chicago in association with the Otho S.A. Sprague Memorial Institute. He was the first African American to teach at the University of Chicago. He rose to Assistant Professor in 1923, and later to Associate Professor. Julian also served as a pathologist at Provident Hospital in Chicago, rising to Chief Pathologist.
In 1926, Julian was among the first to receive a John Simon Guggenheim Fellowship award for study abroad. He conducted his research in laboratories at the University of Basel, Switzerland and at the Staatlichen Serotherapeutischen Institut in Vienna from 1926 to 1927. He was appointed to study “the chemical and immunological specificity of proteins isolated from organs as an approach to a study of the fundamental nature of immunity phenomena, particularly the relation of chemical constitution to biological specificity.” Eva, Gloria, and Julian, Jr. accompanied him to Europe, residing in Paris while Julian conducted his research.
Following the Lewis family's return to the United States, Julian continued his work on immunochemistry at the University of Chicago. He contributed to numerous scientific and medical journals and his work was featured in Life and Time. He was awarded a grant from the Julius Rosenwald Fund to complete a book titled The Biology of the Negro, published in 1942 by the University of Chicago Press. The book was a groundbreaking investigation of contemporary scientific data and literature on African-American physiology and pathology that resisted and rebuked scientific notions of racial inferiority. Julian Lewis left the University of Chicago in 1943.
In addition to Provident Hospital, Julian worked at St. Catherine's Hospital in East Chicago, St. Margaret Hospital in Hammond, Indiana, and finally as director of the pathology department at Our Lady of Mercy Hospital in Dyer, Indiana. He was the first African American inducted into the scientific fraternity Sigma Xi and medical fraternity Alpha Omega Alpha.
Eva Overton Lewis died on October 29, 1945. Julian Herman Lewis died on March 6 1989.
Scope Note
The Eva Overton Lewis and Julian Herman Lewis, MD, PhD Collection is organized into three series:
Series I: Julian Herman Lewis Papers
Series II: Eva Overton Lewis Papers
Series III: Lewis Family Papers
The collection includes personal ephemera, correspondence, photographs and negatives, one DVD, newspapers, textiles, and memorabilia. Materials date between circa 1887 and 2015, with the bulk of the material dating between the 1890s and the 1940s. The collection is primarily a family collection, documenting the personal lives of Eva, Julian, their parents, and their children. It is a record of middle and upper-class African-American life in Chicago and Cairo, Illinois in the first half of the 20th century. Records of Julian Herman Lewis' research, teaching, and clinical work are much less extensive. Of note is correspondence and ephemera dating to the period when the Lewis family lived in Europe during Julian's Guggenheim Fellowship. This material documents the experiences of an African-American family in 1920s Paris, Basel, and Vienna. Explanatory notes made by a Lewis family descendant (likely Elise Evans Gorun) are found throughout the collection, especially among the correspondence.
Series I, Julian Herman Lewis Papers, is divided into three subseries: 1) Personal Ephemera, 2) Correspondence, and 3) Professional. Subseries 3 is further subdivided into records of Julian Herman Lewis' work at the University of Chicago and his Guggenheim Fellowship. Materials are arranged chronologically in each subseries.
Series II, Eva Overton Lewis Papers, is divided into two subseries: 1) Personal Ephemera, and 2) Correspondence. Materials are arranged chronologically.
Series III, Lewis Family Papers, is divided into 12 subseries:
1) Cordelia O. Lewis
2) John Calhoun Lewis
3) Lynn Lewis
4) Anthony Overton
5) Gloria Lewis
6) Julian H. Lewis, Jr.
7) Lewis Family Ephemera
8) Lewis Family Correspondence
9) Travel Ephemera
10) Photographs and Audiovisual Materials
11) Artifacts and Textiles
12) Oversize Documents
The first six subseries are personal papers of, or records about, Lewis family members other than Eva and Julian. Subseries seven to ten contain material pertaining to both Eva and Julian, as well as other family members. Correspondence between Eva and Julian is found in subseries eight. The artifacts and garments in subseries 11 most likely belonged to Eva Overton Lewis. Subseries 12 contains items such as diplomas, certificates, and maps belonging to various members of the Lewis family, as well as an alphabetical arrangement of newspapers saved by the family because they contain mention of a family member or a significant world event. Among the newspapers are issues of The Chicago Bee, published by Anthony Overton.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Hektoen, Ludvig. Papers
Ricketts, Howard Taylor. Papers
Rosenwald, Julius. Papers
University of Chicago Press. Records
Subject Headings
Lewis, Julian Herman; Overton, Anthony, -1946; African American business enterprises; African American business enterprises--Illinois—Chicago; African American businesspeople; African American businesspeople--Illinois--Chicago; African American families; African American families--Illinois—Chicago; African Americans--France--Paris--History--20th century; African American history; African American life; African Americans--Illinois--Chicago; African Americans--Illinois--Chicago--History--20th century; African Americans--Illinois--Chicago—Newspapers; African Americans--Illinois--Chicago--Social conditions--20th century; African Americans--Illinois--Chicago--Social life and customs--20th century; African Americans--Illinois--Social conditions--20th century; African Americans in medicine; African Americans in the newspaper industry; African American women; African American women--France--Paris--History--20th century; African American women--History--20th century; African American women--Illinois--Chicago--Societies and clubs; African American women--Societies and clubs; Chicago history of science and medicine; Illinois—Cairo
INVENTORY
- Series I: Julian Herman Lewis Papers
  - Subseries 1: Personal Ephemera
    - Hunting and drivers licenses; draft card, 1919, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Crisis issues featuring Julian Lewis, July 1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Douglass National Bank cancelled checks and statements, 1923-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Douglass National Bank deposit slip and clipping about Guggenheim fellowship, 1924, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Life insurance policy, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sigma Pi Phi – Ninth convention program, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Douglass National Bank collateral security statement and savings account book, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Douglass National Bank deposit slip, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Chicago Whip newspaper clipping – Mention of Julian Lewis' appointment as director of Douglass National Bank, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Swiss Bank documents, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Chi Delta Mu fraternity, Gamma Chapter – Lecture program, June 1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Obituary for Cordelia O. Lewis – Newspaper clipping, July 1933 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Obituary for Cordelia O. Lewis written by Julian Lewis – Manuscript, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Reproduction of portrait of Ivan Petrovitch Pavlov, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - West Virginia State College commencement program – Julian Lewis address, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Louisville Municipal College commencement program – Julian Lewis address, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper clippings mentioning John Calhoun Lewis and Julian Lewis, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper clipping about Julian Lewis, circa 1943 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Publications and manuals about microscopes, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Julian Lewis obituary, Chicago Tribune, March 9, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Julian Lewis memorial program, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Biographical essay about Julian Lewis written by great grandchild, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Reproduction of photograph of H. T. Ricketts, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - “Mutation as a Cause of Disease,” by Tage Kemp – Photostat, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Subseries 2: Correspondence
    - Letter - Julian Lewis to Mercer [?], September 20, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Telegram – Julian Lewis to Cordelia O. Lewis, October 1, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Letter – Ruth Hazelton to Julian Lewis, June 26, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Letter – William Morrow to Julian Lewis, May 10, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Telegram – John Calhoun Lewis to Julian Lewis, August 20, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Letter – Emma L. Minnis to Julian Lewis, August 27, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Telegram – Savory to Julian Lewis, September 1, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Letter – Julian Lewis to John Calhoun Lewis and Cordelia O. Lewis, September 13, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Letter – Marie Amélie to Julian Lewis, September 18, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Letter – Cordelia O. Lewis to Julian Lewis, October 12, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Letter – Louise Young [née Lewis] to Julian Lewis, October 14, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Envelope to Julian Lewis, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Postcards to Julian Lewis, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Letter – Marie Werner to Julian Lewis, January 3, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Letter – Charles S. Johnson to Julian Lewis, January 11, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Letter – Louise Young [née Lewis] to Julian Lewis, January 27, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Letter – Cordelia O. Lewis to Julian Lewis, January 28, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Letter – John Calhoun Lewis to Julian Lewis, January 29, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Letter – Anthony Overton to Julian Lewis, February 16, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Letter – Martha Witschi to Julian Lewis, March 6, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Letter – Charles Shaw to Julian Lewis, April 23, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Letter – Julian Lewis to Cordelia O. Lewis, April 3, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Letter – Julian Lewis to Director of Victory Life Insurance Co., April 10, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Letter – Julian Lewis to Cordelia O. Lewis, May 9, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Telegram to Julian Lewis, May 14, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Letter and credit note – Swiss Bank Corporation to Julian Lewis, May 17, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Postcard – L. Söll [?] to Julian Lewis, June 29, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Letter – J. H. Branham to Julian Lewis, July 19, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Letter – Emma L. Minnis to Julian Lewis, July 25, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Letter – George C. Ellis to Julian Lewis, August 5, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Letter – Anthony Overton to Julian Lewis, August 18, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Letters – Victory Life Insurance Co. matters, V.D. Johnston and Anthony Overton to Julian Lewis, August 26-27, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Letters – Victory Life Insurance Co., V.D. Johnston to Julian Lewis, September 22-23, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Letter fragment to Julian Lewis, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Letter – Julian Lewis to Lewis family, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Letter – John Calhoun Lewis to Julian Lewis, July 13, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Letter – Cordelia O. Lewis to Julian Lewis, April 7, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Letter – Cordelia O. Lewis to Julian Lewis, June 10, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Letter – John Calhoun Lewis to Julian Lewis, July 2, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Letter – Gloria Lewis to Julian Lewis, July 21, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Letters – Gloria Lewis to Julian Lewis, August 1931 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Letters – Julian H. Lewis, Jr. to Julian Lewis, August 2-6, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Letter – Cordelia O. Lewis to Julian Lewis, September 30, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Letter – Cordelia O. Lewis to Julian Lewis, November 1, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Greeting cards to Julian Lewis, 1932 and 1942 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Letter – A. L. Jackson, Provident Hospital to Julian Lewis, March 25, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Letters – Cordelia O. Lewis to Julian Lewis, April 3-18, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Letter – John Calhoun Lewis to Julian Lewis, May 23, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Postcard – John Calhoun Lewis to Julian Lewis, July 5, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Letter – George Ellis to Julian Lewis, August 19, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Letter – John Haskins, Jr. to Julian Lewis, November 1, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Letter – John Calhoun Lewis to Julian Lewis, May 2, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Letter – Julian Lewis to John Calhoun Lewis, May 8, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Letter – Julian Lewis to family, June 19, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letter – John Calhoun Lewis to Julian Lewis, June 23, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Letter – John Calhoun Lewis to Julian Lewis, March 30, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Letter – Rita Burton to Julian Lewis, circa August 1943 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Letter – Unidentified to Julian Lewis, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 3: Professional
    - Sub-subseries 1: University of Chicago
      - Rush Medical College commencement program – Julian Lewis fellowship appointment, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Fellowship award, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Board of Trustees minutes mentioning Julian Lewis – Photocopies, 1915-1943 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - TIAA Handbook of Life Insurance and Annuity Policies for Teachers – Copy belonging to H. Gideon Wells, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - University of Chicago Address List, October 1925 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - “The Immunological Properties of Alcohol-Soluble Vegetable Proteins” – Proof, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - University of Chicago Weekly Calendar – Lewis lecture, “Causes of Variations in Disease among Races,” November 21, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Science Service – “Says Race Determines Disease Resistance,” 1926 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Letters – Greetings from colleagues in UChicago Department of Pathology to Julian Lewis, December 1926 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Christmas card – H. Gideon Wells to Julian Lewis, circa 1926 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Letter – E. Long to Julian Lewis, February 13, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Letter – Bret Ratner to Julian Lewis, February 24, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Letter – H. Gideon Wells to Julian Lewis, March 11, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Letter – H. Gideon Wells to Julian Lewis, August 26, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Letter – Julian Lewis to H. Gideon Wells, September 11, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Robert Maynard Hutchins inauguration program, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Reappointment letter, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Reappointment letter, December 1935 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Reproduction of painting by Maude Phelps Hutchins, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Photographs – University of Chicago hypnosis research, Life Magazine article, circa 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Sub-subseries 2: John Simon Guggenheim Fellowship
      - Letter of introduction, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship, April 12, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Letter of introduction, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation – Photostats, April 12, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Letter - Guggenheim Foundation to Julian Lewis, June 22, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Letters – E. Berger and Professor Doerr, Hygienisches Institut der Universität Basel to Julian Lewis, September 1-9, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Telegram – E. Berger to Julian Lewis, circa 1927 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Letter – Julian Lewis to Professor Doerr, September 10, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Letter – E. Berger to Julian Lewis, September 16, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Chemistry notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Study schedule and account ledger, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Series II: Eva Overton Lewis Papers
  - Subseries 1: Personal Ephemera
    - Lawrence Business College certificate of membership, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - University of Chicago undergraduate course book, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Eva Overton Lewis calling cards and Press Pass, circa 1910s and 1920s (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Calling cards from others, circa 1920s (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Baby cereal feeding instructions, circa 1920s (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Memorandum books, circa 1920-1924 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Alpha Kappa Alpha booklets, 1923 and 1925 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Alpha Kappa Alpha Boulé Banquet menu in shape of ivy leaf, 1924, Name and address of Georgiana Simpson written on back (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Douglass National Bank cancelled checks and statements, 1924-1928 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - American Express statement, December 1926 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - List of addresses, circa 1926-1933 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - American Express statements, March and June 1927 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Concert program – Marian Anderson at Orchestra Hall, Chicago, November 18, 1929 [Sponsored by Theta Omega, the graduate chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha.] (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Real estate contract, October 1930 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Edward Sanatorium, Naperville, Illinois – Menus/meal slips, circa 1931 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Edward Sanatorium, Naperville, Illinois – Menus/meal slips and newspaper receipts, August-November 1931 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Apartment rental payment receipts, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Chicago Public Library invoice, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Insurance documents, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Ivy Leaf Club, Zeta Chapter, Alpha Kappa Alpha – Constitution and bylaws, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2: Correspondence
    - Postcard – Geraldine Hodges to Eva Overton [Lewis], June 10, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Envelopes, 1916-1927 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Letter - H. R. Smith to Eva Overton [Lewis], August 24, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Letter – A. B. to Eva Overton, September 12, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Postcard – Bessie Rucker Davis to Eva Overton, September 3, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Letter – Lucy [?] to Eva Overton [Lewis], September 19, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Postcard – John W. Davis to Eva Overton [Lewis], September 7, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Letter – Ida Wells Cabell Overton to Eva Overton Lewis, September 13, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Letter – Eleanor Rivers to Eva Lewis, April 15, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Certificate of stillbirth for baby boy and letters of condolence, June 1919 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Letter – Eleanor Rivers to Evan Lewis, August 11, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Wedding anniversary card – Eleanor Rivers to Eva Overton Lewis, September 14, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Card – Allie Mae Hall to Eva Lewis, circa 1920s (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Card – Eva Lewis to Jessie Faucett, circa 1920s (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Cards – Louise Young [neé Lewis] to Eva Lewis, circa 1920s (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Envelopes, 1920-1931 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Cards to Eva Lewis, 1920-1934 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Letters between Dr. Evans and Eva Lewis, May 12, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Letter – Ida M. Langston to Eva Lewis, July 6, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Letter – Cordelia O. Lewis to Eva Lewis, July 11, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Letter – Anthony Overton to Eva Lewis, December 4, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Letters – Jessie Redmon Fauset to Eva Lewis, May 3, 1924 and October 2, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Letter – Eleanor Rivers to Eva Lewis, January 18, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Letter – Carrie Bryant Johnson to Eva Lewis, September 3, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Letter – Jessica D. Morris to Eva Lewis, October 8, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Carte Pneumatique – Bowman to Eva Lewis, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Postcard – George Ellis to Eva Overton, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Letter and receipt – Bedell Millinery Department, January 15, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Letter – Margaret [?] to Eva Lewis and note, February 9, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 37)